Guide to the Consumer Reports. William S. Taylor papers, 1932-1973 and undated RL.11824
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. William S. Taylor papers
1932-1973 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11824
0.5 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. William Sentman Taylor was professor of psychology at Smith College and active in cooperative societies in the Northampton, Mass. area. The William S. Taylor papers include correspondence, clippings, pamphlets, business papers, committee reports and other printed materials that relate primarily to the operation and administrative activities of the Northampton Consumers Association and its relations with other regional consumer groups and cooperative societies. Topics include consumer education and protection, cooperative-run enterprises including book clubs and mail order. Organizations represented include Consumers' Research, the Eastern Cooperative League and Springfield Consumers Cooperative. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General files; Northampton Consumers Association
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. William Sentman Taylor was professor of psychology at Smith College and active in cooperative societies in the Northampton, Mass. area.
William Sentman Taylor was born in 1894 in New Jersey. He attended Gettysburg College (BS 1916), Harvard (MA 1920, PhD 1921) and the University of Wisconsin (MS 1923). Taylor served as professor and department head of philosophy at the University of Maine (1923-1926) before joining the psychology department at Smith College in 1926, where he taught until retiring in 1962. He died in 1976. A specialist in abnormal psychology, Taylor published a number of books and articles as W.S. Taylor. Smith College currently awards in his honor the William Sentman Taylor Prize for "significant work in human values, a quest for truth, beauty and goodness in the arts and sciences" to a student annually.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. William S. Taylor papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Arthur Kallet papers
Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers
Consumer Reports. Frances Warne papers
Collection Overview
The William S. Taylor papers include correspondence, clippings, pamphlets, business papers, committee reports and other printed materials that relate primarily to the operation and administrative activities of the Northampton Consumers Association and its relations with other regional consumer groups and cooperative societies. Topics include consumer education and protection, cooperative-run enterprises including book clubs and mail order. Organizations represented include Consumers' Research, the Eastern Cooperative League and Springfield Consumers Cooperative.
Consumer advocacy; Consumer education; consumer protection; Cooperative societies -- New York (State); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Taylor, W.S. (William Sentman), 1894-1976; Consumers' Research, Inc.
- General Files, 1932-1951 and undated; 1
  - Consumers' Research, 1932-1940 (Box 1)
  - Consumers' Research--Article: Consumers' Research As an Aid to Selective Buying, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Consumers' Research--Strike, 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1951; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Council for Cooperative Development--How to Put on a Tea or Tasting Party, undated (Box 1)
- Northampton Consumers Association, 1935-1973 and undated; 2
  - Consumers Mail-Order Cooperative, 1935-1938 (Box 1)
  - Contact sheets, 1935-1966 (Box 1)
  - Cooperative Book Club, 1937-1943 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1970 (Box 1)
  - Eastern Cooperative League, 1942-1949 (Box 1)
  - General: Constitution, committee reports, etc., 1936-1973 (Box 1)
  - General: Constitution, committee reports, etc., 1937-1972 and undated (Box 2)
  - Springfield Consumers Cooperative, 1938-1946 (Box 1)
  - Springfield Consumers Cooperative, 1938 (Box 2)